# Michael Armstrong

#### **Staff Accountant**

Los Angeles, CA michaelarmstrong4\_u8h@indeedemail.com (818) 398-0486

My many years of experience in financial duties managing multiple priorities and six in Accounts Receivable has prepared me for a position as a Staff Accountant for your company.

This includes financial and customer service exposure in insurance, banking, information technology, and implantable medical devices.

I have a Bachelor of Science degree in Business Administration with an emphasis in Finance and a minor in Speech Communication with experience in Microsoft Office 2010. My accounting regimen included 21 semester units of accounting and Quickbooks.

My background includes heavy use of SAP and CCH.

#### #readytowork

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

# Work Experience

### **Staff Accountant**

Green Hasson Janks - Los Angeles, CA April 2019 to March 2020

- Posted checks, wires, credit card and Ach payments in CCH software.
- Processed retainer and payment adjustments.
- Created Cash Receipts Report and reconciled to sub ledger to inform managers and partners of incoming daily cash.
- Reconciled Federal Express and UPS statements to expense clients of firm.
- Created and worked Overlooked and Missing Payment Report to keep managers and partners informed of past due invoices.
- Served as key player to resolve all billing and collection issues.
- Heavy financial research using data in CCH software.
- Handled responsibility of taking accounts off hold in order to bill clients for additional services.
- Prepared detailed client statements for bill managers and accounting staff.
- Processed and reconciled write offs, credit memos, and miscellaneous charges including non-sufficient funds checks to monthly work in progress report to aide in month end close process.
- Given license on newly acquired software to implement and manage day to day Accounts Receivable transactions.
- Created complex Pivot Tables for internal members of the firm to clarify financial and billing information of clients.
- Tracked credit card fees on pay roc report and emailed to Accounts Payable weekly.
- Prepared check and wire requests for Accounts Payable to refund over payments and unused retainers to domestic and international clients.
- Ad Hoc special projects for senior management.

### **Accounts Receivable/Credit/Collections Analsyt**

Pacific Coast Lighting (LAMPSPLUS) - Chatsworth, CA December 2018 to February 2019

- Posted checks, wires, adjustments and credit card payments including write offs.
- Made collection calls from aging and shipping reports to obtain payment.
- Handled accounts with payment terms such as COD, CIA, and Net 30.
- Collected from Big Box retailers to clear balances due.
- Transferred money. Interaction with international accounts and check refund requests.
- Created aging reports. Created batches and made month end journal entries.
- Set up and processed credit applications.
- Responsible for creating monthly statements for customers and sales force.
- Attended monthly collection meeting with CFO.

#### **Receivables Medical Collector**

White Rabbit Partners/Klean Treatment Centers - West Hollywood, CA March 2018 to May 2018

- Collected fees for outpatient and inpatient detoxification services of Long Beach facility to increase revenue
- Mailed UB04 and 1500 claim forms with supporting medical records to insurance companies for payment.
- Called payers on low customary payment and COB Explanation of Benefit summaries to process claims quicker.
- Researched claims in Sigmund software.
- Documented billing and collection activities in Sigmund and on spreadsheets.
- Reconciled refund requests against G/L to ensure accuracy and to locate discrepancies.
- Responded to claim correspondence to make collection activities more effective.
- Assisted Team Lead with statement and invoicing to develop efficiency in processing.
- Adhered to collection goals under heavy micro-management.
- Prepared and submitted denied claims for first level appeal.
- Supported audit team in appealing claims to obtain a greater payout from Out of Network providers.
- Created aging and revenue reports using Sigmund software.

### A/R/Credit/Risk/Collections Support Analyst

Wella/Coty - Los Angeles, CA August 2017 to January 2018

- Supported four domestic and international Senior Credit Associates in all their endeavors.
- Made B2B collection calls and emailed dunning letters to beautification offices.
- Worked heavily using 12 functions of SAP including Excel to reduce Days Sales Outstanding.
- Handled credit card disputes and audited account statements.
- Performed heavy research and reconciliations to resolve account delinquencies.
- Ad hoc assignments and reports in a fast paced environment.
- Worked heavily with Customer Service, Sales, and Management in the revenue cycle.
- Prepared credit notes on High Profile accounts for customer service.
- Referred bad debt to a third party collection agency.
- Created aging reports in SAP to monitor balances due for 30, 60 90, and 120 day past due invoices.
- Ran D&B reports and assisted in preparing terms for accounts interested in a line of credit.
- Performed declined credit card charges on behalf of Finance using new Cyber Source software.
- Assisted Team Lead in managing and collecting on late High Profile accounts.

### **Accounts Receivable Credit & Collections Analyst**

J2Global - Los Angeles, CA August 2016 to June 2017

- Given exclusive responsibility of total collection effort on a large newly acquired account.
- Made B2B collection calls and emailed delinquency letters on past due domestic and foreign invoices.
- Worked heavily with Excel aging reports and Net Suite to reduce Days Sales Outstanding.
- Researched and reconciled accounts to obtain balances due for 30, 60, 90 and 120 day past due invoices.
- Assisted management in improving the efficiency of collection processes.
- Special projects as assigned. Adapted to a fast paced environment.
- Auto documentation of account activity in Net Suite.
- Heavy interaction with Account Managers to bring accounts current and advised clientele on customer service issues.
- Created Aging Reports
- Collected \$1,000,000 in a six month effort on 1500 past due accounts in US and foreign currencies.
- Coordinated project to financially transfer accounts from US to U.K. using foreign currencies .
- Collected on declined credit card charges.

### **Medical Collector(Contractor)**

Diagnostic Labs & Radiology - Burbank, CA November 2015 to December 2015

- Made collection calls and sent out delinquency letters on a portfolio of 300 accounts.
- Worked heavily with Excel creating ledgers from proprietary software.
- Researched and reconciled government accounts to obtain balances due.
- Assisted management in improving the efficiency of collection processes.
- Auto documentation and of accounts regarding updates in collection efforts.

### **Accounts Receivable/Credit & Collections Analyst**

Saint Judes Medical - Sylmar, CA February 2014 to March 2015

- Handled accounts in arrears amounting to 25 million dollars to reduce DSO.
- Updated and manipulated Excel Spreadsheets using SAP for management review.
- Offset debits and credits at month end to meet company's financial goals.
- Made B2B collection calls on all commercial accounts in arrears.
- Heavy Emails and invoicing in Outlook and SAP. Check requests as assigned.
- Obtained Proof of Deliveries on shipments of products using SAP and Federal Express.
- Account Statement preparation in SAP. Special Projects as assigned.
- Assisted management in improving the efficiency of collection processes.
- Auto documentation of accounts regarding updates of collection efforts.

#### **Credit & Collections Analyst(Contractor)**

Disney/Buena Vista Home Entertainment - Glendale, CA June 2013 to July 2013

#### Responsibilities

- Collected on high volume accounts \$400,000 in arrears to reduce DSO for team.
- Completed weekly reports in Excel and Disco (SAP) to update past due invoices.
- Daily Ad Hoc Projects

Skills Used

SAP, WINDOWS 7, MICROSOFT OFFICE 2010, DISCO

### **Underwriter(Contractor)**

Intuit - Woodland Hills, CA February 2012 to August 2012

- Underwrote 250 new mobile applications a day on new company product in Oasis.
- Handled limits of credit up to 10K.
- Cancelled fraudulent accounts and pended new applications using FICO scores.
- Assessed the risk of merchant accounts to determine fraud.

### **Regional Credit & Collections Representative**

Ryan Herco Flow Solutions

February 2011 to August 2011

- Made 50 B2B collection calls a day to reduce commercial delinquencies.
- Processed credit card payments and ACH wires.
- Worked on Top Forty management report weekly on 60 & 90 day aging.
- Emailed, Scanned, & Faxed documents to customers and sales.
- Worked interactively with outside and inside sales to reduce credit balances.
- Used Excel to create spreadsheets to reduce delinquencies and credit balances.
- Heavy use of Mincron and Lotus notes with detailed information.
- Ran D&B reports to make credit decisions on customers limit of credit.
- Resolved credit balances on daily wash off sheets.
- Heavy phone and customer service interaction.

#### Collector

Cyber Defender - Los Angeles, CA February 2010 to February 2011

- .Performed outbound and inbound collection calls to resolve delinquencies on accounts.
- .Updated spreadsheets with credit card payments collected on assigned Que.
- .Reconciled large delinquencies to reduce DSO.

#### **Collector(Contractor)**

Quest Diagnostics - Valencia, CA August 2009 to January 2010

- .Resolved claim disputes and collected from providers, members, and brokers.
- .Worked interactively with the claims and appeals department to resolve delinquencies.
- .PCP changes, ID card requests, benefit and eligibility disclosures to providers.

### **Mortgage Collector(Contractor)**

Bank of America - Simi Valley, CA March 2009 to August 2009

- Resolved mortgage delinquencies with heavy use of customer service.
- Worked interactively with all departments of the organization.
- Heavy data entry and oral communication in a paperless environment.
- Updated and documented loans in a high pressure call volume environment.
- Took 60-90 calls a day on incoming dialer set up for loan modifications.

- Was within top four collectors on monthly performance report for team.
- Established repayment plans and settlements.
- Handled billing inquires while educating borrowers on account terms.

### **Accounting Clerk/Patient Financial Services**

Medtronic Diabetes - Northridge, CA October 2001 to September 2008

- Assisted Lean Sigma Black Belts to improve operating efficiency for company.
- Participated in system enhancement and inputting of refund checks in SAP.
- Posted 150 SAP entries a day to reduce backlog of denials using CPT codes.
- Manager of Accounts Receivable implemented suggestion on batching EOB's.
- Special Projects as assigned in Excel for a manufacturing environment.
- Posted insulin pump upgrades in SAP.
- Found over payments on SAP Delimit Report on special project for A/P.
- Prepared documents for SOX audits.

#### Education

### **Bachelor of Science in Finance Minor: Speech Communication**

California State University Northridge - Northridge, CA 1982 to 1987

# **Accounting Licenses**

# **Licensed Fire & Casualty Insurance Broker**

### Skills

- SAP, MICROSOFT OFFICE 2010, PROPRIETARY SOFTWARE (3 years)
- NETSUITE (1 year)
- Quickbooks (1 year)
- Cyber Source (Less than 1 year)
- AS400, EPICOR PROPHET, (1 year)
- Accounts Receivable
- Receivables
- AR
- Cash Application
- Account Reconciliation
- · Debits & Credits

### Certifications and Licenses

### **COMPUTER CERTIFICATION**

October 2011 to Present

BURBANK ADULT SCHOOL... MICROSOFT OFFICE EXCEL 2010 BEGINNER AND ADVANCED, QUICKBOOKS FOR ACCOUNTING

#### **MANAGEMENT TRAINING**

FRED PRYOR CAREER TRACK: MANAGEMENT TRAINING FOR THE NEW MANAGER

### **H&R BLOCK TAX COURSE 2018**

October 2018 to Present

#### **Driver's License**

### **CCH Cloud Based Network**

April 2019 to March 2020

#### Assessments

### **Accounting Skills: Basic Principles — Proficient**

March 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to prepare financial records according to federal policies.

Full results: <a href="https://share.indeedassessments.com/">https://share.indeedassessments.com/</a>

share to profile/90fed1f27fee44d52335bf661ea6dc55eed53dc074545cb7

# Accounting Skills: Bookkeeping — Highly Proficient

April 2020

Calculating and determining the accuracy of financial data. Full results: <a href="https://share.indeedassessments.com/attempts/">https://share.indeedassessments.com/attempts/</a> afb0db216e768356b9b46e89aaf4ecd4eed53dc074545cb7

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.

### Additional Information

THE PEOPLE CONCERN

WALK FOR JUVENILE DIABETES

LOS ANGELES MISSION CORPORATE INVOLVEMENT DAY.

**VOLUNTEER INCOME TAX ASSOCIATION** 

PROFESSOR FOR A DAY 2018... SCHOOL OF BUSINESS... CAL STATE NORTHRIDGE